Indiana University President's Office records, 1963-1990 C459
Indiana University Archives
Indiana University President's Office records
1963-1990
1971-1987
Indiana University Archives
Indiana University. President
C459
310.1 cubic feet 314 boxes
John W. Ryan served as Indiana University's president for 16 years. This collection includes correspondence files, and administrative records related to the management of various offices and departments on campus and of the regional campuses.
Access Restrictions
Select files closed to researchers. Advance notice required for access to collection.
Restricted files are listed where they would fall in the intellectual organization of the collection but are housed in Boxes 284-297 and 308-309.
Administrative History
John William Ryan was born on August 12, 1929, in Chicago, Illinois. He received a bachelor's degree from the University of Utah in 1951. Ryan came to Indiana University as a graduate student in 1951. He received a master's degree in 1958 and a Ph.D. in 1959, both in political science, at IU. He was a research analyst in the Department of Revenue for the Commonwealth of Kentucky, 1953- 55; research associate in the I.U. Program in Public Administration in Thailand, 1955-57; Assistant Director of the Institute of Training for Public Service on the Bloomington Campus, 1957-58; Associate Director, Bureau of Government, University of Wisconsin, 1958-62; Executive Assistant to the President and University Secretary, University of Massachusetts, Amherst, 1962-63; Vice- President for Academic Affairs, Arizona State University, 1963-65; and Chancellor, University of Massachusetts, Boston, 1965-68. In July 1968 Ryan become IU Vice- President and Chancellor for Regional Campuses and was elected fourteenth president of Indiana University on January 26, 1971. One of the hallmarks of Ryan's administration was the development of the campuses at Fort Wayne, South Bend, Gary (Northwest), Kokomo, and Jeffersonville (Southeast) from extension centers to degree-granting divisions. During his tenure, a cooperative program of long standing in Richmond was launched as the University's sixth regional campus.
After announcing his retirement as President in 1986, Ryan continued an active public role as a liaison, public speaker, and representative for IU. Dr. Ryan passed away on Saturday morning, August 6, 2011 at IU Health Bloomington Hospital. He was married for 62 years to his wife Patricia, and the couple had three children: Kathleen, Kevin, and Kerrick.
Portions of this Biography taken from "The Investiture of John W. Ryan as Fourteenth President of Indiana University" Program.
Arrangement
This collection is made up of two series, Administrative records and Correspondence files. The Administrative records are arranged alphabetically by folder title, while the Correspondence series is organized into three subseries as follows: Mail Logs, Chronological files, and Alphabetical files. Restricted files, with the exception of boxes 118-122, are located in Boxes 284-297 and 308-309 but are listed where they would fall in the intellectual organization of the collection. Boxes 118-122 are made up entirely of restricted IU Foundation files, but remain in sequence.
Scope and Content Note
The collection consists of two series: Administrative records and Correspondence files with the majority of the records dating from John Ryan's tenure as Indiana University President from 1971-1987. A small portion of the files within the collection contain items from before and after his presidency dating from 1963 through 1990.
The Administrative records (1963-1990) are arranged alphabetically by folder title and then chronologically.
The majority of the collection consists of files relating to the various administrative offices, academic departments and schools which comprise the university and include administrative correspondence, policies and annual reports. Schools and departments prominently featured include: College of Arts and Sciences; Division of Continuing Education; the Graduate School; the Schools of Law, Business and Music and Public and Environmental Affairs (SPEA); and School of Medicine and International Programs. These are often are listed under their own title ("History, Department of" or "Law, School of"). The Regional campuses of Indiana University are featured prominently in the collection and are filed under "regional campuses" followed by the specific campus. Likewise, other files relative to the various campus administrative departments include the Office of Affirmative Action, Alumni Association, and Athletics, Halls of Residence, and Safety Division.
Other sections of the collection relate to various associations and outside entities with which the University interacted. These include other universities such as Purdue University and the University of California. Files relating to the City of Bloomington and the State of Indiana include information relating to statewide programs, legislature, and correspondence with political figures such as mayors, governors and senators. Topics prominently featured include: the state budget, Indiana Legislative workshops and task forces and Higher Education Telecommunication Systems (IHETS). Others include the Association of American Universities (AAU); Association of College and University Business Officers (ACUBO); and Association of State Universities and Land Grant Colleges (ASULGC), the National Collegiate Athletic Association (NCAA), the Indiana Commission for Higher Education, and the Midwest Universities Consortium for International Activities (MUCIA).
Large portions of this series contain files on campus committees, including both student and administrative committees. Some which may be of interest include the Board of Aeons, Committee on Dedications and Ceremonies; Committee on Campus Beauty and the University Committee on Names.
Other portions of this series are more topical in nature. The "faculty" files contain information on governance, promotions, statistical data, collective bargaining, and retirement information while the "Ryan, John" files contain invitations, calendar and travel information, and miscellaneous other information about the president. Other subjects of interest include those on enrollment, campus budget, computers and computing, campus bus service and parking, and university reorganization.
The Correspondence files (1969-1987) are arranged chronologically and then alphabetically and divided into three sub-series: Mail Logs, Chronological files, and Alphabetical files. Each of these contain the outgoing correspondence from the President's Office, arranged wither chronologically or alphabetically by correspondent.
Related Material
Additional records such as newsletters, annual reports, bulletins, and publications may be accessed in the Archives of Institutional Memory
Related photographs may be available in the University Archives Photographs Database
Acquisition Information
Accession numbers: 0784, 0442, 0403, 0343, 1006, 1036, 1040, 0860, 1000, 0412, 1062, 1072-1074, 1089-1090, 1031, 1014-1016, 0290, 0325, 0768, 1002, 0413, 1022-1023, 1012, 0420, 1001, 0418, 1007, 1024, 1027, 1032, 1033, 1061, 1064, 1091, 1063, 9035-9038, 2013/003
Appraisal
Account records regarding things like the purchase of coffee and copy machines were discarded, and most payroll and personnel files were removed and shredded. Transcripts, grade reports, and documents containing social security numbers were also removed and shredded. Four cubic feet of invitations, addressed to Ryan, were sampled and discarded.
As additional SSNs, account numbers, student records, etc., are discovered, they will be pulled and destroyed or redacted, as appropriate.
College presidents --Indiana --Archives.; College presidents --Indiana --Correspondence.; Universities and colleges --Indiana --Administration.; Indiana University, Bloomington; Indiana University -- Administration; Ryan, John W. (John William), 1929-2011 -- Archives; Ryan, John W. (John William), 1929-2011 -- Correspondence; Indiana University. President -- Archives; Indiana University. President -- Records and correspondence
- Administrative records, 1963-1990; undated (Box 1)
  - A, General (Box 1)
    - 1971-1982 (Box 1)
    - 1983 (Box 1)
    - 1984 (Box 1)
    - 1985 (Box 1)
    - Jan-June, 1986 (Box 1)
    - July-Dec, 1986 (Box 1)
    - 1987 (Box 1)
  - Abr, 1971-1987 (Box 1)
  - Ad, 1971-1987 (Box 1)
  - Ag, 1971-1987 (Box 1)
  - Ale, 1971-1987 (Box 1)
  - Alli, 1971-1987 (Box 1)
  - All, 1971-1987 (Box 1)
  - Am, 1971-1987 (Box 1)
  - Anders, 1971-1987 (Box 1)
  - Andr, 1971-1987 (Box 1)
  - Ar, 1971-1987 (Box 1)
  - At, 1971-1987 (Box 1)
  - Au, 1971-1987 (Box 1)
  - As, 1971-1987 (Box 1)
  - Academic (Box 1)
    - 1971-1972 (Box 1)
    - 1972-1973 (Box 1)
    - 1973-1974 (Box 1)
    - 1974-1975 (Box 1)
    - 1975-1976 (Box 1)
    - 1976-1977 (Box 1)
    - 1977-1978 (Box 1)
    - 1978-1979 (Box 1)
    - 1979-1980 (Box 1)
    - 1980-1981 (Box 1)
    - 1981-1982 (Box 1)
    - 1982-1983 (Box 1)
    - 1983-1984 (Box 1)
    - 1984-1985 (Box 1)
  - Academic Affairs (Office of) (Box 1)
    - Annual Report, 1970-1971 (Box 1)
    - 1971-1972 (Box 1)
    - Annual Report, 1971-1972 (Box 1)
    - Dean's Retreat, Inn of Four Winds, March 15-16, 1973 (Box 1)
    - Annual report, 1972-1973 (Box 2)
    - May 1973-December 1973 (Box 2)
      - (Folder 1) (Box 2)
      - (Folder 2) (Box 2)
    - 1973-1974 (Box 2)
    - Annual report, 1973-1974 (Box 2)
    - 1974-1975 (Box 2)
  - Academic Bankruptcy, 1969-1977 (Box 2)
  - Academic Building Systems, 1971-1972 (Box 2)
  - Academic Development Plan, 1974 (Box 2)
  - Academic Garb, 1985 (Box 2)
  - Academic Guide- Replaced pages, 1978-1979 (Box 2)
  - Academic Review, 1975 (Box 2)
  - Academy for Educational Development (Box 2)
    - General (Box 2)
      - 1971-1972 (Box 2)
      - 1972-1973 (Box 2)
      - 1973-1974 (Box 2)
      - 1974-1975 (Box 2)
      - 1979 (Box 2)
    - Occasional Papers, 1971-1987 (Box 2)
  - Academies in the Public Service carry forward, 1983 (Box 2)
  - Accelerator (Box 2)
    - 1971-1972 (Box 2)
    - 1972-1973 (Box 2)
    - 1973-1974 (Box 2)
  - Accounting (Box 2)
    - General, 1971-1978 (Box 2)
      - 1971-1972 (Box 2)
      - 1972-1973 (Box 2)
      - 1973-1974 (Box 2)
      - 1974-1975 (Box 2)
      - 1975-1976 (Box 2)
      - 1976-1977 (Box 2)
      - 1977-1978 (Box 2)
    - Lists of Accounts, 1980 (Box 2)
  - Accreditation and Commission on Accrediting, 1971 (Box 2)
  - Action, 1971 (Box 2)
  - Address to the University (Box 2)
    - 1978 (Box 2)
    - 1981 (Box 2)
  - Administrative A Z, 1976 (Box 2)
  - Administrative Appointments (Box 2)
    - General, 1973 (Box 2)
      Conditions Governing Access
      (RESTRICTED)
    - Staffing moratorium (Box 3)
      - 1972-1973 (Box 3)
      - 1973-1974 (Box 3)
  - Administrative Committee, 1971-1972; (two folders) (Box 3)
  - Administrative Computing (Box 3)
    - 1983 (Box 3)
    - 1985 (Box 3)
    - 1986-1987 (Box 3)
  - Administrative Manual (Box 3)
    - General (Box 3)
      - 1971-1972 (Box 3)
      - 1972-1973 (Box 3)
      - 1973-1974 (Box 3)
      - 1974-1975 (Box 3)
      - 1975-1976 (Box 3)
      - 1977-1978 (Box 3)
    - Guide Regional Campuses, 1978-1979 (Box 3)
  - Administrative Retreat, 1986 (Box 3)
  - Administrative Reviews, 1983 (Box 3)
  - Administrative Supplements, 1971-1987 (Box 3)
  - Administrators (Box 3)
    - General, 1971-1980 (Box 3)
    - External Activities, 1980-1982 (Box 3)
  - Admissions and Recruitment (Office of) (Box 3)
    - 1971-1975 (Box 3)
    - 1975-1976 (Box 3)
    - 1976-1977 (Box 3)
    - 1977-1978 (Box 3)
    - 1978-1979 (Box 3)
    - 1979-1980 (Box 3)
    - 1980-1983 (Box 3)
    - 1983-1984 (Box 3)
  - Admissions (Box 3)
    - General (Box 3)
      - 1980 (Box 3)
      - 1984 (Box 3)
      - 1985 (Box 3)
      - 1986 (Box 3)
      - 1987 (Box 3)
    - Inquiries and problems (Box 3)
      - 1982 (Box 3)
      - 1983 (Box 3)
  - Advertising, 1981 (Box 3)
  - Board of Aeons (Box 3)
    - General (Box 3)
      - 1971-1972 (Box 3)
      - 1972-1973 (Box 3)
      - 1973-1974 (Box 3)
      - 1974-1975 (Box 3)
      - 1975-1976 (Box 3)
      - 1976-1977 (Box 3)
      - 1977-1978 (Box 3)
      - 1978-1979 (Box 3)
      - 1979-1980 (Box 3)
      - 1980-1981 (Box 3)
      - 1981-1982 (Box 3)
      - 1982-1983 (Box 3)
      - 1983-1984 (Box 4)
      - 1984-1985 (Box 4)
      - 1985 (Box 4)
      - 1985-1986 (Box 4)
      - 1986 (Box 4)
    - Constitution and letterhead, no date (Box 4)
    - Recognition dinner, April 2, 1985 (Box 4)
  - Aerospace Research Applications Center (Box 4)
    - 1970-1971 (Box 4)
    - 1971-1972 (Box 4)
    - 1972-1973 (Box 4)
    - 1974-1975 (Box 4)
    - 1975-1976 (Box 4)
    - 1977-1978 (Box 4)
  - Aerospace, 1987 (Box 4)
  - Affirmative Action Program (Box 4)
    - 1971-1972 (Box 4)
    - 1972-1973 (Box 4)
    - 1973-1974 (Box 4)
    - 1973-1974 (Box 4)
    - 1974-1975 (Box 4)
  - Affirmative Action (Office of) (Box 4)
    - 1974, (3 folders) (Box 4)
    - 1974, (3 folders) (Box 5)
    - Annual report, 1974-1975 (Box 5)
    - 1975-1976 (Box 5)
    - Annual report, 1975-1976 (Box 5)
    - 1974 (Box 5)
    - 1973 (Box 5)
    - 1975 (Box 5)
    - 1976 (Box 5)
    - Correspondence, 1976-1977 (Box 5)
    - 1976-1977 (Box 5)
    - Correspondence Rhome, 1976-1977 (Box 5)
    - Annual report, 1977-1978 (Box 5)
    - 1977-1978 (Box 5)
    - HEW pre award contract compliance review task force, 1978 (Box 5)
    - 1978-1979, (2 folders) (Box 5)
    - Annual report, 1978-1979 (Box 5)
    - 1979-1980 (Box 5)
    - Annual report, 1979-1980 (Box 5)
    - 1980-1981 (Box 5)
    - 1981 (Box 5)
    - 1981-1982 (Box 5)
    - 1982-1983 (Box 5)
    - 1984 (Box 5)
    - 1984-1985 (Box 5)
    - 1985 (Box 6)
    - 1, 985-1986 (Box 6)
    - 1986 (Box 6)
    - 1986-1987 (Box 6)
  - Affirmative Action Schedule, 1972-1973 (Box 6)
  - Afghanistan (Box 6)
    - 1973-1974 (Box 6)
    - 1971-1972 (Box 6)
    - 1972-1973 (Box 6)
    - 1974-1975 (Box 6)
    - 1974-1975 (Box 6)
  - African Series, 1971 (Box 6)
  - African Studies (Box 6)
    - 1971-1972 (Box 6)
    - 1972-1973 (Box 6)
    - 1973-1974 (Box 6)
    - 1974-1975 (Box 6)
    - 1975-1976 (Box 6)
    - 1976-1977 (Box 6)
    - 1977-1978 (Box 6)
    - 1978-1979 (Box 6)
  - African Affairs Advisory Council, 1972 (Box 6)
  - Afro-American Affairs (Box 6)
    - 1971-1972 (Box 6)
    - 1972-1973 (Box 6)
    - 1973-1974 (Box 6)
    - 1974-1975 (Box 6)
    - 1975-1976 (Box 6)
    - 1976-1977 (Box 6)
    - 1977-1978 (Box 6)
    - 1978-1979 (Box 6)
    - 1979-1980 (Box 6)
    - 1980-1981 (Box 6)
    - 1981-1982 (Box 6)
    - 1982-1983 (Box 6)
    - 1983-1984 (Box 6)
  - Afro American Affairs Office (Box 6)
    - 1983 (Box 6)
    - 1986 (Box 6)
  - Afro American Affairs, Annual Report (Box 6)
    - 1976-1977 (Box 6)
    - 1978-1979 (Box 6)
    - 1979-1980 (Box 6)
    - 1980-1981 (Box 6)
  - Afro American Studies (Box 6)
    - 1971-1972 (Box 6)
    - 1972-1973 (Box 6)
    - 1983 (Box 6)
  - AGB Self-Study – Notes from Committee, 1979 (Box 6)
  - Age Discrimination, 1979 (Box 6)
  - Agency for International Development (AID), 1974-1975 (Box 6)
  - Agenda, Miscellaneous Materials, 1977 (Box 6)
  - Aged and Aging (Center on) (Box 6)
    - General (Box 6)
      - 1969-1971 (Box 6)
      - 1971-1972 (Box 6)
      - 1975-1976 (Box 6)
      - 1976-1977 (Box 6)
      - 1977-1978 (Box 6)
      - 1978-1979 (Box 6)
      - 1979-1980 (Box 6)
      - 1980-1981 (Box 6)
      - 1982 (Box 6)
    - Planning and Program Development Board, 1979 (Box 6)
  - Air Force Institute of Technology, Board of Visitors, 1979 (Box 6)
  - Air Transportation (Box 6)
    - 1971-1972 (Box 6)
    - 1973-1974 (Box 6)
  - Al, 1982 (Box 6)
  - Alabama (University of), 1981 (Box 6)
  - Alcohol Use, 1981-1982 (Box 7)
  - Ali Frazier Fight, 1971 (Box 7)
  - All University Committee on Names (Box 7)
    - 1971 (Box 7)
    - 1971-1972 (Box 7)
    - 1972-1973 (Box 7)
      Restricted
  - Alumni Association and Alumni Miscellaneous (Box 7)
    - General (Box 7)
      - 1971-1972 (Box 7)
      - 1972-1973 (Box 7)
      - 1973-1974 (Box 7)
      - 1974-1975 (Box 7)
      - 1975-1976 (Box 7)
      - 1976-1977 (Box 7)
      - 1977-1978 (Box 7)
      - 1978-1979 (Box 7)
      - 1979-1980 (Box 7)
      - 1980-1981 (Box 7)
      - 1981-1982 (Box 7)
      - 1982-1983 (Box 7)
      - 1983-1984 (Box 7)
      - 1984 (Box 7)
      - 1985 (Box 7)
      - 1985-1986 (Box 7)
      - 1987 (Box 8)
    - Annual Report (Box 8)
      - 1970-1971 (Box 8)
      - 1971-1972 (Box 8)
      - 1972-1973 (Box 8)
      - 1973-1974 (Box 8)
      - 1974-1975 (Box 8)
      - 1975-1976 (Box 8)
      - 1976-1977 (Box 8)
      - 1977-1978 (Box 8)
      - 1978-1979 (Box 8)
      - 1980-1981 (Box 8)
    - Alumni Camp (Box 8)
      - 1980 (Box 8)
      - 1981-1982 (Box 8)
      - 1983 (Box 8)
    - Deceased lists (Box 8)
      - 1974 (Box 8)
      - 1975-1976 (Box 8)
      - 1976-1977 (Box 8)
      - 1977-1978 (Box 8)
      - 1978-1979 (Box 8)
      - 1979-1980 (Box 8)
      - 1980-1981 (Box 8)
      - 1981-1982 (Box 8)
      - 1982 (Box 8)
    - Distinguished Alumni Service Award (DASA) (Box 8)
      - 1971-1972 (Box 8)
      - 1972-1973 (Box 8)
      - 1973-1974 (Box 8)
      - 1974 (Box 8)
      - 1975 (Box 8)
      - 1976 (Box 8)
      - 1976-1977 (Box 8)
      - 1977-1978 (Box 8)
      - 1978-1979 (Box 8)
      - 1979-1980 (Box 8)
      - 1980-1981 (Box 8)
      - 1982-1983 (Box 8)
      - 1983-1984 (Box 8)
      - 1985 (Box 8)
      - 1982 (Box 8)
      - 1983 (Box 8)
      - 1982 (Box 8)
      - 1984 (Box 8)
      - 1985 (Box 8)
      - 1986-1987 (Box 8)
    - Handbook for Alumni Club Leaders, 1983 (Box 8)
    - Summary Report, 1984 (Box 8)
  - Alumni Leaders Conference, 1975-1976 (Box 8)
  - Alumni Legislative Council Luncheon, 1975 (Box 8)
  - Alumni Magazine Articles on Ryan - Correspondence, 1970-1975 (Box 8)
  - Alumni Office Island Steel - Lake Monroe project (Box 8)
    - 1973 (Box 8)
    - 1975-1976 (Box 8)
  - Alumni Relations (Box 8)
    - 1973 (Box 8)
    - 1982 (Box 8)
    - July-Dec, 1982 (Box 8)
    - Jan-Mar, 1983 (Box 8)
  - American (Box 8)
    - 1971-1972 (Box 8)
    - 1972-1973 (Box 8)
    - 1973-1974 (Box 8)
    - 1974-1975 (Box 8)
    - 1975-1976 (Box 8)
    - 1976-1977 (Box 9)
    - 1977-1978 (Box 9)
    - 1978-1979 (Box 9)
    - 1979-1980 (Box 9)
  - American Academy of Arts and Sciences (Box 9)
    - 1971-1972 (Box 9)
    - 1971-1972 (Box 9)
  - American Assemble of Collegiate Schools of Business, 1979 (Box 9)
  - American Association of University Professors (Box 9)
    - 1953-1954 (Box 9)
    - 1954-1955 (Box 9)
  - American Association of University Women (Box 9)
    - 1971-1972 (Box 9)
    - 1972-1973 (Box 9)
    - 1975-1976 (Box 9)
  - American Astronomical Society, 1971-1972 (Box 9)
  - American Council for Coordinated Action, 1979 (Box 9)
  - American Council of Learned Societies (Box 9)
    - 1972-1973 (Box 9)
    - 1973-1974 (Box 9)
    - 1974-1975 (Box 9)
    - 1979-1980 (Box 9)
    - 1982 (Box 9)
    - 1986 (Box 9)
    - 1987 (Box 9)
  - American Council of Life Insurance (Box 9)
    - Annual Meeting, 1976 (Box 9)
    - Arden House Conference, 1976 (Box 9)
    - General (Box 9)
      - 1980-1984 (Box 9)
      - 1980 (Box 9)
      - 1984 (Box 9)
  - American Council on Education (Box 9)
    - American Universities and Colleges, 1971-1972 (Box 9)
    - A Fact Book on Higher Education, 1971-1972 (Box 9)
    - 1971-1972 (Box 9)
    - 1972-1973 (Box 9)
    - 1973-1974 (Box 9)
    - 1974-1975 (Box 9)
    - Annual meeting, 1975 (Box 9)
    - A Fact Book on Higher education, 1974-1975 (Box 9)
    - 1975-1976 (Box 9)
    - Ace Committee on Taxation, 1975-1976 (Box 9)
    - Guide to Professional Development Opportunities for College and University, 1976 (Box 10)
    - 1976 (Box 10)
    - Higher education and national affairs, 1976-1977 (Box 10)
    - Washington D.C., 1976 (Box 10)
    - The Search for Alternatives, 1974 (Box 10)
    - 1976-1977 (Box 10)
    - January-June, 1977 (Box 10)
    - July-December, 1977 (Box 10)
    - 1977-1978 (Box 10)
    - Higher Education and National Affairs, 1977-1978 (Box 10)
    - 1977-1978 (Box 10)
    - Higher Education and National Affairs, 1978-1979 (Box 10)
    - 1978-1979 (Box 10)
    - 1978-1979 (Box 10)
    - 1979 (Box 10)
    - 1979-1980 (Box 11)
    - Higher Education and National Affairs, 1980 (Box 11)
    - 1980-1981 (Box 11)
    - Annual meeting, 1980 (Box 11)
    - 1981 (Box 11)
    - Higher Education and National Affairs, 1981 (Box 11)
    - 1981-1982 (Box 11)
    - January-March, 1982 (Box 11)
    - April-June, 1982 (Box 11)
    - July-December, 1981 (Box 11)
    - ACE WX Poss after Washington D.C., 1981 (Box 11)
    - Higher Education and National Affairs, 1982-1983 (Box 11)
    - 1982-1983 (Box 11)
    - Annual Meeting, 1983 (Box 11)
    - 1983 (Box 11)
    - 1984 (Box 11)
    - 1984-1985, (2 folders) (Box 11)
    - 1985 (Box 11)
    - 1986 (Box 11)
    - Board Meeting, 1986 (Box 11)
    - Board of Director's meeting, 1986 (Box 11)
    - May 7-8, 1986 (Box 11)
    - July 30-31, 1986 (Box 11)
    - 1987 (Box 11)
  - American Federation of Labor CIO (AFL / CIO) (Box 11)
    - 1971-1972 (Box 11)
    - 1972-1973 (Box 11)
    - 1973-1974 (Box 11)
    - 1974-1975 (Box 11)
  - American Federation of State County and Municipal Employees (Box 11)
    - 1971-1972 (Box 11)
    - 1973-1974 (Box 11)
    - 1974-1975 (Box 11)
    - 1975-1976 (Box 11)
    - 1979-1980 (Box 11)
    - 1980-1981 (Box 11)
  - American Federation of Teachers Local (Box 11)
    - IU Northwest, 1971-1972 (Box 11)
    - IU Bloomington, 1971-1972 (Box 11)
  - American Federation of Teachers (Box 11)
    - 1972-1973 (Box 11)
    - 1973-1974 (Box 11)
    - 1974-1975 (Box 11)
    - 1975-1976 (Box 11)
    - 1976-1977 (Box 11)
    - 1977-1978 (Box 11)
    - 1978-1979 (Box 11)
    - 1979-1980 (Box 11)
    - 1980-1981 (Box 12)
    - 1981 (Box 12)
    - 1981-1982 (Box 12)
    - 1982 (Box 12)
    - 1982-1983 (Box 12)
    - 1983-1984 (Box 12)
    - 1984 (Box 12)
    - 1985 (Box 12)
    - 1986 (Box 12)
  - American Fletcher Corporation, 1971-1972 (Box 12)
  - American Fletcher National Bank (Box 12)
    - 1971-1972 (Box 12)
    - 1972-1973 (Box 12)
  - American Forum for International study, 1971-1972 (Box 12)
  - American Fund for Dental Education (Box 12)
    - 1971-1972 (Box 12)
    - 1972-1973 (Box 12)
    - 1973-1974 (Box 12)
    - 1974-1975 (Box 12)
  - American Fund for Dental Health (Box 12)
    - 1973-1974 (Box 12)
    - 1974-1975 (Box 12)
    - 1975-1976 (Box 12)
    - 1976-1977 (Box 12)
  - American Institute of Biological Sciences, Annual Meeting, 1981 (Box 12)
  - American Institute of Chemists, 1971-1987 (Box 12)
  - American Medical Technologists, 1971-1972 (Box 12)
  - American Red Cross (Box 12)
    - 1982 (Box 12)
    - 1983 (Box 12)
  - American Security Council, 1971-1987 (Box 12)
  - American Society for Public Administration (Box 12)
    - 1984 (Box 12)
    - 1985 (Box 12)
    - 1986 (Box 12)
    - 1987 (Box 12)
  - American Society of Composers, Authors and Publishers, 1971-1987 (Box 12)
  - American Universities and Colleges, 1981 (Box 12)
  - American Universities Field Staff (Box 12)
    - General (Box 12)
      - 1971-1972 (Box 12)
      - 1972-1973 (Box 12)
      - 1973-1974 (Box 12)
      - 1974-1975 (Box 12)
      - 1975-1976 (Box 12)
      - 1976-1977 (Box 12)
      - 1977-1978, (2 folders) (Box 12)
      - 1978-1979 (Box 12)
      - 1979-1980 (Box 12)
      - 1980-1981 (Box 12)
      - 1981 (Box 13)
    - Annual Meetings (Box 13)
      - 1972 (Box 13)
      - 1975, (3 folders) (Box 13)
      - 1976 (Box 13)
      - 1977, (2 folders) (Box 13)
      - 1979 (Box 13)
    - Financial Reports (Box 13)
      - General File, 1973-1977 (Box 13)
      - 1972-1973 (Box 13)
      - 1973-1974 (Box 13)
      - 1975 (Box 13)
      - 1976-1977 (Box 13)